[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOT]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
- [ENGINES REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [GUNSHOT]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
I'm sorry because I'm the one
who brought bad luck
to our family.
Because of me...
I gave our father a wound
that I can never erase.
[SCREAMS] Help!
RJ!
So this is what you do
to helpless people?
You turn them into a business!
- [BLOWS LANDING]
- [GRUNTING]
- [KICK LANDS]
- [SLINGSHOT TWANGS]
Mister Babot, you're safe now.
Thank you
for saving my husband.
Thank you for saving us.
I will repay you
for the rest of my life.
Let's give her an hour.
I'll find a way
to get her kicked out of here.
- Hey!
- [BOTTLES BREAKING]
If you have a problem with me,
say it to my face.
- Fine!
- [SMACKS]
That's enough!
Stop it! Ibyang! Go home!
[IBYANG] Stop it!
Why are you meddling
in our fights, anyway?!
Romy, let go of me!
I have to get back
at that woman!
Stop it, that's enough!
[IBYANG] I have to get back
at her!
[MATET] Shh, that's enough!
- [IBYANG] Let me go!
- What happened?
- [MATET] Madam got
- Let me go!
into a fight with Miss Betchay.
[DJANGO CHUCKLES]
Why do you look like that?
Don't tell me you lost?
If your dad hadn't stopped me...
I'm sure they'd be grieving
over her by now!
Then why did you go home?
'Cause Paquito told her to.
Ibyang, since when did you
become Papa's minion?
- Move it!
- Ouch!
- I got hit, too!
- [DJANGO CHUCKLING]
- [ROSANNA] Go on, girls.
- [WOMAN] Thank you, boss!
Just my luck.
[PAQUITO] Betchay,
what really is your problem?
Over the years
we've been together...
I'm always the one who gives.
I'm always the one
who understands.
I'm the one making sacrifices,
and I'm the one they blame?
I'm the one working,
but I'm still the bad guy!
The problem with you...
...is you married someone
with a gangster son!
Hey, Gabo's useful now!
- He's got a job!
- What?
You know, he paid
the hospital fees.
- All of it?
- Mm-hmm!
200,000 pesos?
What kind of work does he have?
- Well, I'm suspicious of it.
- Oh?
- I think it's illegal work.
- Huh?
'Cause Gabo never does
anything good!
Maybe he mugged someone.
Or maybe...
He kidnapped someone!
Or he stole!
[DJANGO] So, should I
destroy Betchay?
Ibyang, just say the word,
and I'll do it.
I mean, I already shot
Gabo's father.
I'll shoot his stepmother next.
[DJANGO CHUCKLES]
Let me finish our fight.
We're just getting started.
But that father of yours...
We'll talk when he gets home.
That Paquito might start
to think
that because I'm not
his real wife,
he can just embarrass me
in public.
No way!
He was the same with Mama
back then...
...until she got tired and left.
You think I can't leave
your father?
I can if I want!
Don't!
You know, out of all the women
Papa has ever had...
You're the only one
who can keep up with him!
I'm even impressed with you!
We should drink to that!
Come on! Being dramatic
doesn't suit you.
Here.
- [BOTTLES CLINK]
- That's it.
I should get going.
Wait! Wait, wait.
Wait a minute.
Here. It's your pay for today.
I even included a tip!
- Really? This is mine?
- Yeah! Yeah!
Wow! Thank you.
[PAQUITO STAMMERING]
Uh, Betchay. Wait.
Do you want to earn more?
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
Join our group.
[CHUCKLES DRYLY]
Come on now, Paquito.
I'd never do anything illegal
just to make money.
You won't be doing anything
of the sort.
I've got a different job
for you.
What are you saying?
[PAQUITO] You've got skills
I can put to use.
No stealing? No killing people?
Absolutely not.
And Betchay...
You'll earn ten thousand pesos
if you carry out
the task we give you.
So what do you think?
Want to join our group?
I'll think about it.
[CHAIR SCRAPING]
[MUSIC SWELLING]
[MUSIC FADES]
[GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING]
[GUNSHOTS ECHOING]
- [YOUNG RUDY] Run!
- [YOUNG BELINDA] Aah!
[RAPID GUNFIRE]
Come on, hurry!
Gabriel. Gabriel, listen to me.
Listen to Mommy, okay?
Mommy loves you so much.
No matter what happens,
always stay good.
Don't forget everything
I taught you, okay?
[YOUNG GABO]
Okay, Mommy.
[YOUNG BELINDA] Have mercy
on my family! Take me instead!
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [GUNSHOT]
[SHOUTS] Ma!
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
- [GLOOMY MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SCREAMS] Mommy!
[YOUNG RUDY] Gabo...
Son, are you having
nightmares again?
[VOICE BREAKING]
It's Mommy...
Me too, son.
I miss your mommy as well.
Forgive me, son.
I couldn't save your mother.
Please, forgive me.
[YOUNG GABO] I miss Mommy.
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR CREAKS, THUDS]
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[GABO INHALES DEEPLY]
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
[SNIFFLES]
[GABO SIGHS]
Pa.
What are you still doing up?
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
I'm just getting some air, son.
[STAMMERS] W-Why are you
still awake at this hour?
The past still gives me
nightmares, Pa.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
I can't get over what
happened to Mama.
[SIGHS] You know, son...
I know what's on your mind.
You're thinking about...
about how to take revenge
on those people.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Just stop, son.
Forget about it.
Don't...
Don't gamble your life
just for revenge.
[GABO] No, Pa.
I have to find out
who killed my mother.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I have to get justice
for her death.
[SIGHS HEAVILY]
I want to know the persons
responsible for her death.
Who killed my mother, Pa?
Who?!
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Pa, answer my question.
Do you know the people
who killed my mother?
Do you?!
No, son.
I-I have no idea.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[GABO BREATHING HEAVILY]
I won't sit back
and do nothing, Pa.
I won't let my mother's death
go without justice.
I'll track them down.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I'll avenge my mother's death.
Son, just let it all go.
Don't... Don't get yourself
into danger.
[STAMMERS]
I-If they come after you...
I can't bear to lose you.
I don't care who they are.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I won't stop until I find them.
Not until justice is served
for my mother.
I won't rest, Pa.
I'll find them.
[MUSIC SWELLING]
[MUSIC BECOMES THRILLING]
[FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
- Django.
- Yes, Pa?
Do you know
what Gabo's new job is?
Who cares about that jerk?
I don't care
what that bastard does.
Find out what he does.
Because, according to Betchay,
Gabo earned 200,000 pesos...
...in just one day.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
What could be the reason
Gabo made that much money?
He makes risky moves.
He could've mugged a bank,
or robbed a pawnshop.
It's so hard for us
to earn money,
while Gabo gets money
that easily?
That's why you have to
find out what he does, Django!
Who knows, he might slowly
be robbing us of our income.
One day,
we might just wake up...
...and Gabo and his group
already control Ginintuang Lupa.
I won't let that happen.
Gabo can't overpower us.
He'll have to deal
with my fists first!
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[OBJECTS RUSTLING, THUMPING]
Oh, Sam? You're going to work?
But I booked a spa retreat
for you to de-stress,
and bond with me!
I need to go to the office.
People from Internal Affairs
are there.
They'll tell me
if they'll dismiss me or not.
They can't dismiss you.
You are a good agent!
Who punched a criminal
who's in our custody.
Well, I believe...
not that I'm justifying
your actions,
but I know there is a reason...
...why you did it!
You will be fine.
Okay?
[GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING]
Dad. I know aside from Sam,
you already have
a lot of problems,
one of which is Ginintuang Lupa.
Well, I just...
...want you to know
that I am onto something.
Wait, um...
You'll visit the family of...
...Rudy? Rudy Magtibay?
Yes, Dad, the family
of the man who was shot.
And...
[MAX SIGHS]
Please, Dad.
Trust me on this one.
Max, you know I believe in you.
But whatever you're planning...
Don't be like Sam...
...who's now dealing
with a problem she created.
Don't be like her, please?
[KAREN] I know what Sam
is going through.
I can feel her hurt
'cause I've only seen
her drink like that last night!
We can't blame her.
We worked so hard
to catch Mr. Chan,
but she ended up suspended.
[PIA] Oh?
Where did you go last night?
[SEBASTIAN CLEARS THROAT]
[SEQIOA] Ma'am Pia,
it's nothing.
We just went out
for some drinks.
Mm! You celebrated?
But celebrated what?
You catching Mr. Chan?
It's not like that, Ma'am Pia.
Um...
Jacinto's troubled
with her situation,
- so we had drinks.
- Just her situation?
You'll be in trouble, too!
You're accomplices, aren't you?
Now that Internal Affairs
will investigate Jacinto,
you'll get entangled in this
when the truth comes out.
Instead of reporting Jacinto,
what did you do?
You sided with her!
Because we knew our plan
will have a positive result.
And that is correct, isn't it?
We caught Mr. Chan.
It did have a positive result.
Jacinto's suspended!
Look, Jacinto's jeepney
is arriving,
and it's headed to the dumps!
You should all ride it, hm?
Here, I already signed this.
It's done.
- Sir, thank you.
- Alright.
- [POLICE 1] Good morning, sir.
- [POLICE 2] Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
- [SEBASTIAN] Director!
- Yes?
- Sir.
Can we talk?
[DELGADO] You seem troubled.
[SEBASTIAN] Because, sir,
Internal Affairs
will interview
my almost-girlfriend.
[DELGADO] Almost-girlfriend?
Who? Sam?
Hm.
She's getting interviewed later
because of what she did.
[SEBASTIAN] Sir,
she's already suspended,
but there's still an interview?
For what?
To pressure her?
Sir, remember,
if Sam didn't take action,
we wouldn't have been able
to catch Mr. Chan.
Sebastian.
This is what we do to people
who don't follow the protocol.
I know that, sir.
But if we're going
to let internal affairs
interview Sam,
they should let Sam
explain her side.
Actually, sir, NCIA
shouldn't be focusing on Sam.
They should focus on Mr. Chan.
We need to make him talk.
We will be able to do that.
We just have to be sure
that he is safe.
So we will move him
to a safe house.
Because Mr. Chan
is requesting to be part
of the witness
protection program.
Is that so, sir?
Then I'm going
to escort Mr. Chan.
I'll do that to protect
Sam's trump card.
You can't get near Mr. Chan.
Because you have
a close connection
to the group
that violated the protocol.
Almost girlfriend.
Right?
Almost.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
Have mercy on my family.
Take me instead.
[YOUNG BELINDA WHIMPERS,
SCREAMS]
[GUNSHOTS]
[GABO] They deprived my mom
of justice.
But we are not the only ones
experiencing this cruelty.
A lot of poor people
go through the same thing.
It needs to stop.
There's only one person
who can help me.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[PAPANG] Our country
is too chaotic.
The chaos around is rampant.
[TOMAS] Even our government
can't contain the surge
of criminals anymore.
That's why Anino is here.
To help clean our country.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[DRAWER CLOSES]
[MUSIC BECOMES STIRRING]
[CLANKS]
[RUBBER BAND STRETCHES]
Gabo, join us.
Come on, have your breakfast.
[GABO] Good morning.
- [DANTE] Eat with us.
- So, do you have work today?
Uh...
I'm not sure, Auntie.
I'm waiting for their call
to see if I'm scheduled today.
- Mm-hmm.
- [WATER SLOSHING]
Gabo, what sort of job
did you end up taking?
[MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING]
You see, Pa...
It's hard to explain.
I do a lot of things.
Sometimes they ask me
to deliver packages,
and other times they ask me
to find certain people.
[TEKLA] Hey, we're finally here!
Ready to join for breakfast!
- It's a beautiful morning!
- Good morning!
- Gabo, what's up?
- Alright, sure thing.
- Breakfast is our first stop.
- Come on, join us here.
Grab some bread.
This is exactly why
we came here.
I'm starving.
- [MAMENG CHUCKLES]
- Hey, give me some!
[TEKLA] Gabo.
- Got a new gig lined up for us?
- I can't say for sure.
Well, I'm still...
I'm still waiting
for their call.
What a bummer.
I hope they ring soon
so we can earn some cash.
[PLAYFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
Gabo, count us in, okay?
We don't want to miss out
this time.
[IPE] There you go again.
You have no faith in Gabo
at all.
He's not the type
to cheat you out of money!
- [TEKLA] Exactly!
- [DANTE] Shh, quiet!
[BETCHAY] What the hell?!
So much noise this early
in the morning!
Do we have any ice here?
Buy some ice for her
so he can freshen up
and chill out.
[DANTE] I'm on it.
[LOUD THUD]
[BETCHAY, DRYLY] Money for your
maintenance meds, sir.
[GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING]
[BETCHAY SCOFFS]
The whole gang is here again.
Taking food that's not yours.
Do you even realize the price
behind that food?
It's my sweat and blood!
- I worked myself to the bone!
- [RUDY] That's enough!
[CHAIR RATTLING, THUDS]
[MAMENG] Rudy...
[GLOOMY MUSIC CONTINUES]
Rudy...
[BANGS ON SCREEN DOOR]
[SCREEN DOOR SLAMS]
Auntie, we'll be outside.
[TEKLA] Right, let's go.
It's too hot in here right now.
It's really hot in here because
there's no air conditioner!
- [TOLITS] Move it!
- Cramming in here doesn't help!
She's really unbearable.
Gabo, why is she always
pissed at us?
[BONG] How wouldn't she be?
Someone here eats like crazy,
just demolishing Gabo's food.
[DABOY]
It's just a bit, though...
[TEKLA]
That's what you call a bit?
You'll get used to it.
That's just how she is.
Try to understand her.
[BINO] So, Gabo,
is there a gig or not?
[TOLITS] Any way to make money?
Not yet.
They haven't called me yet.
Okay, here's what we'll do.
Let's just meet up later, okay?
Gabo, we'll get going now.
- Mmm, sure.
- Come on, let's go.
Let's not waste the day.
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
Excuse me.
Pa.
Is your wound still painful?
It's okay now.
It's starting to heal a bit.
[BADONG] Rudy, the motorcycle's
all fixed up now.
[ELTON]
What's the total bill, Badong?
[BADONG] It's 4,700 pesos,
Mister Elton. All-in.
That's for everything?
Put it here.
Be careful with it.
[KICKSTAND RATTLING]
- Thanks.
- Mister Elton.
Here's the payment
for the bike repair.
That's 5,000 pesos.
It's too much.
You can keep the change.
Thanks.
[RUDY] Gabo, I told you
I'd handle the bill.
It's fine, Pa.
I still have some cash, anyway.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
By the way, Pa...
For your maintenance meds.
- No, no, I can't take that.
- Please, Pa.
That's for you.
I've got some cash remaining.
Thank you.
Where are you going?
I was going to ask a favor.
Can I borrow the bike again
to get to work?
I promise, Pa, I'll be...
I'll be careful.
I won't break it.
You promise
you'll take care of it?
- Yes, Pa.
- Alright, then.
[THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING]
Mister Elton.
I already asked
Papa's permission...
I'll just borrow the bike again.
Where are you headed? The bike
might get messed up again!
it was just repaired!
Elton, let him use it.
He promised that
he'll take care of it. Go on.
- It's okay, son.
- Fine, Rudy.
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[GABO EXHALES]
Take care.
I will, Pa.
Mister Elton.
[ENGINE ROARING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
- [TEKLA] Stay safe, Gabo!
- We'll be right here!
- Agent Chua.
- Yes, ma'am?
Are the Internal Affairs people
here already?
[AGENT CHUA]
They haven't arrived yet, ma'am.
- Okay, thank you.
- Sure.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
You're brave.
I'll give you that.
You really came here
to face the consequences?
I'm only fulfilling part
of my duty.
I'm here to undergo
a fair assessment
and have my actions verified.
Make the most out of it.
For all we know,
this might be your last time.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
There's been far too much
chaos here,
and it's all your fault.
Tiger made an attempt
on Mr. Chan.
The case is getting more
and more complicated
because of you, Jacinto.
This agency would be better off
without you.
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVS]
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[WOMAN] Jeepney!
[JEEPNEY WHOOSHES]
[JEEPNEY, MOTORCYCLE
ENGINE REVVING]
Here's our fare.
For two people, please.
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[WOMAN] Be careful, dear.
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
Where would you like to eat
once we're done with enrollment?
Let's go to
our favorite place, Ma.
[YOUNG GABO] I love you, Mommy.
[YOUNG BELINDA] I love you.
[WOMAN] The restaurant
you love eating at?
- [KID] Yes, Ma!
- [WOMAN] Okay.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
We will buy you
new school supplies.
Walk faster, dear.
Hurry up, son!
- Run, son! [SCREAMS]
- [KID WHIMPERS] Ma...
[GATE CLANKS]
- [KID WHIMPERS] Help!
- Help!
- [MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- Help!
- [KID CRYING]
- Give us your bag!
- Give it!
- [KID SOBBING] Mama!
- Hand it here!
[KID CRYING]
[GOON 1] Lift her up!
- My son!
- [GOON 2] Give me that!
- [SOBBING]
- [INDISTINCT SCREAMING]
- [GOON 1 GRUNTS]
- [GUNSHOT]
[KID] Ma!
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVVING]
[CRYING] Ma! Ma!
Let's go! Hurry, come on!
- [MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVVING]
- [GABO SCREAMING]
[THUDDING]
Ah!
[KID] Help!
- [COUGHING]
- Help us!
Help!
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [GUNSHOT]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
They are very influential.
They'll use all their money
and all their connections.
They will do everything to get
their son out of jail.
Victor, you are going down!
Make sure you'll bring Mr. Chan
to the safe house safely.
Our target is Mr. Chan.
Eliminate anyone who
will try to stop you.
So, you're suspending, huh?
We might get suspended too.
I'd be fine
with only a suspension.
But what if we lost
everything we worked hard on?
I thought you already understood
that it wasn't Sam's fault?
[KICK LANDS]
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [GRUNTING]
- Ah!
- [BLOW LANDS]
Please help my mom!
Help!
Help us!
- What happened?
- She was shot.